片名：博物馆惊魂夜
喂！小心点
Hey, watch it
（故障
这招没用！）
不会吧
oh, come on
嘿
麦克
Hey, Mike!
赖瑞，你好吗？
-Hey, Larry.
-How you doing?
尼克呢？
Have you seen Nicky?
他跟雅莉回去了
I'm pretty sure he went with Erica.
It was hALf day today
今天是职场家长日，只读半天
Parent career Day
（职场家长日）
-嘿
-嘿，进来吧
-Hey.
-Hey. come on in
-你还好吧？
-还好
-You all right?
-Yeah, yeah
怎么没人跟我说
今天是职场家长日？
why didn't anybody tell me
it was career Day?
什么？
尼克说他会告诉你的
what do you mean?
Nicky said he was gonna tell you
我想他忘了
oh, okay, I guess he forgot
他来了
你好吗，赖瑞？
There he is. How are you, Larry?
很好，你呢，唐恩？
Good. How are you doing, Don?
很好
Good
你说这天气够怪的吧？
can you believe this weather?
冷冰冰，像冷冰冰的酷企鹅
chilly, right? chilly, chilly,
chilly willy the penguin
别吵啦
我会跟小可爱说你来了
Leave me ALone. Hey, why don't I go tell
the little corncob you're here
好，谢了
Great. Great, that's great. Yeah, thanks
你未婚夫腰上挂的家伙可真多
wow, your fiance really manages
to squeeze a lot onto that belt
-别闹了
-什么？
-Stop it.
-what?
什么？我是说
他就好像K
what? No, it's like he's...
股票市场的武林至尊
...the Batman of stockbrokers
-他是债券交易员
-债券交易员，抱歉
-Bond trader.
-Bond trader. Sorry
你的虚拟高球练习场进度如何？
Hey, how's it going with that virtuAL-reality
driving range that you wanted to open?
技术面还有待克服
Getting there, still waiting for
the technology to catch up
这不简单，有很多移动的物品
It's not easy,
there are a lot of moving parts
你想尼克会喜欢皇后区吗？
Hey, do you think Nick
would like Queens?
噢，不，赖瑞
你不会又被赶出来了吧？
oh, no, Larry. You didn't get evicted again,
did you?
我没有K
I didn't...
被赶出来，我没有
不，我是说K
...get evicted. I didn't get evicted, no.
I mean, I didn't...
-不，我还没有被赶出来
-赖瑞，听我说
-No, I didn't get evicted yet. It's like--
-Larry, listen to me
尼克不能再忍受这一切了
I don't know how much more
Nicky can take
每隔几个月就换新工作、新住所
Every couple months, it's a new career,
a new apartment
要不是为了尼克，我不会管你
If it wasn't for Nicky, I wouldn't
say anything, I would stay out of it
这么不安定对他不好
It's just, it's too much instability.
It's not good for him
我正在设法解决问题
I'm trying to figure things out
right now, okay?
你要知道
You know...
我不认为尼克该跟你在一起
...I don't think that Nicky
should stay with you
-什么？
-除非你安定下来
-what?
-Just until you get really settled
嘿，爸
Hey, Dad
-准备去冰上溜达了？
-酷啊
-Hey, ready to carve it up?
-cool
好耶，尼克
抄球盘！冲出去！
All right, good!
Take it, Nicky! Break away!
-你搞什么啊？
-小乖，你还好吧？
-what are you doing?
-Hey, Nicky! Are you all right?
-你没事吧？
-我很好，你下去好吗？
-You okay?
-I'm fine. would you get off the ice?
听着，他们的左卫很弱
Listen. Their left defenseman
is a very weak skater
往左去，你就有机会射门
好吗？
So you go left side, you got
a clear shot at the goAL. okay?
-谢了
-好
-cool, thanks.
-All right, man
没事，我们很好
继续比赛吧
we're good here. we're good.
All right. As you were, skaters
加油！
Game on!
我没事
I'm good
你今天表现得超精彩
I'm telling you,
you tore it up out there today
当职业选手绝对没问题
Thinking the NHL is a serious possibility
我不想打曲棍球了
I don't really wanna be
a hockey player anymore
-好吧，那你想做什么？
-债券交易员
-All right. what do you wanna be?
-A bond trader
债券交易员？
A bond trader?
唐恩就是做那个的
他带我去过他办公室
Yeah, it's what Don does.
He took me to his office last week
好吧
That's cool
你想每天穿西装打领带？
So you wanna dress up
in a monkey suit and tie every day?
像个机器人？
Like an automaton robot?
办公隔间里不能打球，太窘了
Trust me, you can't play hockey
in a cubicle. Kind of awkward
他有一间很大的办公室
well, he's got a pretty big office
那不是重点，你喜欢曲棍球的
That's not the point.
come on, you love hockey
我还是喜欢
但当交易员是我的退路
I still like it,
but bond trading's my fallback
你的退路？
Your fallback?
等等，你还没大到要有退路
wait a minute. You're too young
to have a fallback, okay?
还有你是从哪听到这字眼的？
And ALso, where did you ever
even hear that word?
妈跟唐恩有谈过你的阴谋
Mom was tALking to Don
about all your different schemes
她说是阴谋？
She called them schemes?
她说你该找个退路了
She said it was time
you found a fallback
你真的又要搬家了？
Are you really moving again?
我不知道，再说吧
I don't know. we'll see. I mean...
皇后区有些地方挺酷的
...there's some pretty cool places
out in Queens
-是啊
-嘿
-Yeah.
-Hey
尼克，看着我
Hey, Nicky, look at me
看着我
Look at me, man.
I wanna tell you something
我知道我最近状况很多
I know that things have been kind of
up and down for me lately...
你并不好过
...and that's been hard for you
不过我觉得我就快成功了
But I really feel like my moment's coming
and when it does...
到那时，一切都会很顺利
...everything's just gonna come together,
you know?
万一你弄错了呢？
what if you're wrong...
万一你只是个
需要找份工作的普通人呢？
...and you're just an ordinary guy
who should get a job?
这个嘛
All right, well...
我会搞清楚的，好吗？
You know what,
we'll figure it out, okay?
好了，我们去找你妈吧
All right? come on,
let's get you back to Mom's
达理先生，我敢说
我从事这行43年
Mr. Daley, I can honestly say,
in 43 years at this agency...
从未看过你这种履历
...I've never seen a resume
quite like yours
好耶
All right
那并不是赞美
That wasn't a compliment
上面写你当过执行长
It says here you were the cEo...
叫“啪哒集团”
...of Snaptime Industries
能说明一下吗？
care to elaborate on that?
当然，那是我发明的出品集团
啪哒弹指器
Sure. well, that was the umbrella
corporation for my invention, the Snapper
弹一下指头，灯就开
弹一下指头，灯就关
You know, you snap, the lights come on.
Snap, they come off
这不是早就上市了？
Didn't they ALready make that?
不，那是拍掌器
那很显然是K
No, no, that's the clapper,
which, obviously...
剽窃了我们的点子
...stole a bit of our thunder
我个人是看不出有什么差别
Personally, I don't really see
what the big difference is, I mean:
你知道，随便
不过
You know, whatever, but...
不过显然有占很多数比例的人口
这方面有点困难
...apparently there is a significant portion
of the population that has trouble actually...
-不大能够弹指头
-拍掌比较简单
-...snapping.
-clapping's easier
这有待商榷
Debatable
我帮不了你
I can't help you
黛比？
Debbie?
我能叫你黛比吗？
can I call you Debbie? Because...
我一进来就觉得你倍感亲切
...I felt a connection
when I entered this office...
我觉得你对我也有同感
...and I don't know,
I feel like you did too
我对你没感觉
I didn't feel a connection
听着
Look
我明天就要有一份工作
I need a job tomorrow, okay?
要是找不到K
If I don't have one...
反正我就是需要
好吗？
well, I just need it, okay?
我不知道
well, I don't know
可能有个缺
I might have one thing
他们回绝了我派去的每一个人
They've turned down everyone
I've sent over there, but--
太好了
Great
谁知道呢？
--who knows?
你可能会走运
You might get Iucky
-抱歉，你好
-你好
-Excuse me. Hi.
-Hi
我是赖瑞达理
我来找克西傅德瑞克面试
I'm Larry Daley. I've got a job interview
with cecil Fredricks
-他应该还在办公室里
-太好了
-Right. He should still be in his office.
-Great
我是导览员贝嘉贺门
-你好
-I'm Rebecca Hutman. I'm a docent here.
-Hi
-我带你过去吧
-太好了
-Let me point you in the right direction.
-Great
泰迪罗斯福总统，对吧？
Teddy Roosevelt, right?
-对，好眼力
-当然
-Yes, a great visionary.
-Yes, definitely
他是第四任总统，对吧？
He was our 4th president, right?
-是第二十六任
-第二十六任
-Twenty-sixth.
-Twenty-sixth
请勿触碰展品
Please don't touch the exhibits!
I mean...
下等人
Riffraff
贺门小姐
我不能忍受这种混乱
Miss Hutman.
I cannot tolerate this type of chaos
这是一间博物馆
不是K
I mean, this is a museum, not a...
你知道博物馆代表什么吗？
Do you know what “museum” means?
那不是代表
“哇，爸爸，好大的恐龙”
It doesn't mean,
Daddy, it's a big Tyrannosaurus thing
“我能碰他的脚吗？”
不行！
can I touch its leg? No!
拜托你解决问题
work it out, please
-我会的
-谢谢
-will do, sir.
-Thank you
麦菲博士，博物馆总监
Dr. McPhee, the museum director
看来挺风趣的
Seems like a fun guy
拜托管一下你的小孩
control your young, please. can we?
（警卫室）
谁啊？
开玩笑的啦
Hello? Just kidding
你好，我是赖瑞达理
你是傅德瑞克先生？
Hi. I'm Larry Daley.
Are you Mr. Fredricks?
傅德瑞克先生是我爸
Mr. Fredricks was my father
我叫克西
幸会，赖瑞，握手力道不错
I am cecil. Good to meet you, Larry.
Nice firm handshake
我喜欢，这代表一个人的个性
进来吧
I like that. Tells a lot about a man.
come on in
我们就打开天窗说亮话吧
Let's tALk turkey here
博物馆近年亏损连连
The museum is losing money,
hand over fist
我猜现在的孩子
不再喜欢蜡像或填充动物了
I guess kids today don't care about
wax figures or stuffed animALs
所以他们要缩编
就是裁撤K
So they're downsizing,
which is code for firing...
我和夜班警卫
...myself and the other two night guards
他们要找新的警卫来取代我们
They want to replace us
with one new guard
-抱歉
-你又能怎样呢？
-oh, sorry.
-well, what are you gonna do?
见见我两位同事吧
I'd like you to meet
my two colleagues here
雷纳？葛斯？
ReginALd? Gus?
他人呢？我要亲手扁他
where is he? I'll beat him with my fist!
葛斯，这位是赖瑞达理
他要来当新的夜班警卫
Gus, this is Larry Daley, the kid who
wants to be the new night guard
夜班警卫？
Night guard?
介绍所的人说是博物馆的职位
No, the lady at the agency said
this was a museum position
博物馆里最重要的职位
Most important position
in the museum, Larry
他看来像个怪胎
He looks like a weirdie
好警卫，做人却很糟
wonderful guard, terrible people skills
听着，呆瓜，别想耍花招
Now, listen, Iunch box.
Don't try anything funny
我跟拳王对战过九回合
I once went nine rounds
with John L. Sullivan
你才没跟拳王对战过
You never fought John L. Sullivan
in your life
两位，这里有个应征者
Gentlemen, we have
a job candidate here
他的履历很漂亮，态度又积极
He's got an excellent resume,
a winning attitude...
我认为该给他一个机会
...and I say let's give him a shot.
what do you say?
等等，我要想一下
Hang on a sec. I think I might wanna
have a little time just to think it over
你到底要不要工作，呆瓜？
Do you want the job or not, snack shack?
-要，我要这份工作
-欢迎成为夜班警卫，赖瑞
-No, no, I want the job--
-welcome to the night guards, Larry
赖瑞，到二楼等我
Larry, meet me up on the second floor
我穿上护膝带你走一圈
膝盖关节炎
I'll slip into my orthopedics and
give you a little tour. Arthritic knees
年纪大可不好玩，朋友，走吧
Not fun getting old, my friend. Go on
你真认为他可以？
You really think he's the one?
当然
oh, yes
他可以的
He's the one
快跟上，我可是活动力很强的老人
Gotta keep it moving, Larry.
I'm pretty spry for an old man
这是实景模型陈列区
This is the Diorama Room
是啊
oh, yeah
我记得这些小家伙
真可爱
I remember these little guys. cute
克西
cecil!
嘿，克西
Hey, cecil!
-我吓到你了吧？
-是啊
-Did I get you good?
-Yeah
你吓到我了
You got me
说真的，别在这里干蠢事
这玩意很古老了
Seriously, though, no fooling around
in here. This stuff is really old
好了
你也看得出来，最近很冷清
All right, then. As you can see,
it's pretty quiet in here these days
左边是匈奴王阿提拉和匈奴人
on the left there is your Attila the Hun
这里是复活岛的巨石像
And here we have our Easter Island head
嘿
Hey, cecil
这里是非洲哺乳动物陈列室
And this, of course,
is the Hall of African MammALs
是啊
Ah, yes
猴子
我喜欢猴子
Monkeys. I love monkeys
-是啊
-他真可爱
-Yeah.
-Guy's cute
是啊，我们叫他德克斯
他真是K
Yeah, we call him Dexter.
He's quite a little...
可爱
对不对啊，德克斯？
...ball of fun, aren't you, Dexter?
走吧
Moving on
最后，这是法老王阿卡曼拉之殿
And, finally, this is the temple
of the Pharaoh Ahkmenrah
下面那个石棺，法老王就躺里面
And in that tomb right down there,
the pharaoh himself
真有趣
Neat
他后方墙上挂的是
And hanging on the wall behind him...
他最重视的宝贝
阿卡曼拉刻写板
...was his most prized possession,
the Tablet of Ahkmenrah
24K纯金，价值连城
Twenty-four-carat gold.
It's worth a fortune
真酷
very cool
没错
It is indeed, Larry
很酷
very cool
明天下午五点报到
我们会跟你说明你的职责
All right. Report here at 5 tomorrow.
we'll wALk you through your duties
五点，我会到的
okay, 5. I'll be here
走吧
Moving on
是我，我找到工作了
Hey, it's me. So I got a job
真是太好了，什么工作？
Larry, that's great. What is it?
这工作K
It's a job...
在自然历史博物馆里
...at the Museum of NaturAL History
你可以告诉尼克我们不搬家了
Yeah, so you can tell Nicky
that we won't be moving
这是好消息
Larry, this is good news
是啊，明天见了
Yeah, no, definitely.
So I'll see you tomorrow?
-好
-好，再见
-OKay.
-okay, bye
赖瑞？
Larry?
你的钥匙
手电筒
Your keys. Your torch
-好
-把那些绑在腰带上
-Right.
-You'll wanna strap those to your belt
这里晚上会有点吓人
It can get a little spooky
around here at night...
所以你可能会想开几盏灯
...so you might wanna
put a few lights on
手电筒、钥匙，还有什么
All right, flashlight, keys.
what am I for--?
指令手册
The instruction manuAL
手册
Instructions
依顺序来，一、二、三
You start with one, two, three...
四？
Four?
你是在搞笑吗？
Are you cracking wise?
我真该赏你一拳，臭小子
I ought to punch you
in the nose, hopscotch
别闹他了，葛斯
赖瑞，你行吧？
Leave him ALone, Gus.
You got it covered, right, Larry?
我行的
Yeah, yeah, I got it
-你最好是行
-葛斯
-You better get it!
-Gus
照顺序来，要彻底也要快
Larry, do them in order,
do them all and do them quick
还有，最重要的是要记得
别让任何东西进来或出去
And the most important thing of all
to remember: Don't let anything in or out
出去？
out?
祝你好运，孩子
Good Iuck, son
-晚安，葛斯
-臭小子，爱搞笑
-Night, Gus.
-Young buck. cracking wise
走吧
Moving on
喂？
Hello?
喂！
Hello!
检查
check!
check
我是赖瑞
I am Larry
检查，赖瑞，赖瑞K
check! Larry! Larry
星期一！星期一！星期一！
Monday! Monday! Monday!
超级卡车大赛
Monster Truck Rally
克西？
cecil?
很好笑，克西
okay, very funny, cecil!
这是什么，大卫魔术秀吗？
what is this, like a
David copperfield thing?
这真怪
This is weird
克西？
cecil?
快啊
旋转！旋转！
come on. Revolve. Revolve!
姓名？
克西
-Name, please?
-cecil...
傅德瑞克
稍候，拨接中
-...Fredricks!
-One moment. Connecting
-喂
-克西，我是赖瑞达理
-Hello.
-cecil! It's Larry Daley!
赖瑞，有事吗？
Larry. Yes, how can I help you?
恐龙活过来了
The dinosaur-- The dinosaur is alive!
我听不见
I'm having a little trouble
hearing you, friend
“龙舌兰！”
Tequila
恐龙活过来了
The dinosaur's alive!
我该怎么办？
what do I do?
Tell me what to do!
看手册，手册里都有解释
Read the instructions.
It explains everything
我拿到了
okay, I got them!
-明天见
-等等！什么？
-I'll see you tomorrow.
-Wait! What--?
（一、丢骨头）
什么骨头？
what bone?
捡骨头？
Fetch?
玩捡骨头？
Play fetch?
不会吧
No way
-笨笨
-什么？
-Dum-dum.
-Yes?
-你给我糖糖
-给你糖糖？
-You give me gum-gum.
-I give you gum-gum?
新笨笨，给我糖糖
You new dum-dum.
You give me gum-gum
你知道吗？我没有糖糖
okay, you know what?
I have no gum-gum. Sorry
抱歉，还有我不叫笨笨
我叫赖瑞
And my name isn't dum-dum,
my name's Larry
不，你叫笨笨
No, your name dum-dum
你麻烦大了，笨笨
oh, you in trouble, dum-dum
你最好跑跑躲匈匈阿提拉
You'd better run-run
from Attila the Hun-Hun
待会见了，笨笨
See you later, dum-dum
怎么回事？
what is happening?
嘿
Hey
你好吗？
How you doing?
你是K
Are you...?
You're...
莎卡加味？
...“Sakagahwahwaya”?
你是莎卡加味？
You're “Sakagawaya”?
莎卡佳哩！
你是莎卡佳哩？
oh, Sakagawea. You're Sakagawea?
玻璃，我不能K
The glass. I can't...
听到你
...hear you
你听不到？
你听不到我？
You can't...? You can't hear me?
对不起
你帮助路易斯和克拉克K
Excuse me.
“who assisted the Lewis and clark--”
那就是路易斯和克拉克？
而你是K
Right, so that's Lewis and clark
and you're.... Right
你好像K
我是赖瑞
You seem-- I'm Larry
怎么回事？
你知道这是怎么回事吗？
what's going on? what's--?
Do you know what's going on here?
匈奴人
我得要K
Huns. I gotta--
（二、关好狮子
不然他们会吃了你）
嘿，嗨
Hey. Hi
大铜人，嗨，你好啊
Tin Man. Hey. Hi. How you doing?
我新来的，上面写我该关好狮子
不然他们会吃了我
I'm new. It says I'm supposed to
lock up the lions or they'll eat me
你是伽利略？不是？
You're Galileo? No?
观光客
okay...
我是K
Hey, I'm the...
我是新来的，我只想关门收工
Hi. I'm the new guy
and I'm just locking up, so...
如果可以的话
我就看我的书
If it's cool with you
I'm just gonna get my paperwork...
不再烦你们，好吗？
...and be out of your hair, okay?
再检查一次你的腰带
猴子可能偷走钥匙了
“Double-check your belt.
The monkey probably stole your keys.”
猴子
Monkey
喂，你叫什么名字？
Hey. Hey there. Hi.
what's your name? Your name is...
不，回来
No, no, no. come back. come back
德伊？那是你的名字吗？
Dewey? Is that your name, Dewey?
不对，德威？德克斯
No, no, no. what's--? Dewey?
Dexter? Dexter. Dexter, right?
德克斯，把钥匙给我吧？
Hey, Dexter,
you wanna give me those keys?
我只是想锁门
I just want to lock up
对，很好，过来找爸爸
Yes. oh, good. come to Papa
谢谢，能把那些钥匙给我吗？
很好，真是个好孩子
oh, thank you. can I have those keys?
oh, good. what a good boy
好，谢谢你
That's okay. oh, thank you
不、不，没关系
非常、非常感谢你
oh, no, no, no. It's okay.
Thank you very, very much
坏猴子！快停！
Bad monkey. Stop that
那是不对的
你尿完了？
That's not right. Are you done?
你对我有意见吗？
Do you have an issue with me?
因为我就算对人有意见
我也不会乱洒尿
Because if I have a problem with somebody,
I don't pee on them, okay?
还有，我告诉你
钥匙在此
And ALso-- Let me tell you something.
These keys?
德克斯！这不好玩！快还来！
Hey. Dexter, that's not funny.
Give it back
德克斯！快还来！
Dexter. Give--
不要，我知道你在想什么
别那么做，那主意不好
Don't. I know what you're thinking.
Don't do it. Not a good idea
德克斯，我需要那些纸
Not-- Dexter, I need those
别鼓励他
你以为你朋友觉得你很有趣？
Don't encourage him. You think
you're funny for your friends, huh?
怎么，他是头头，你们是观众？
You three guys-- what, he's the ringleader,
you're the audience?
别那么做
Yeah, no. Don't do it, okay?
你！
Lookit-- You!
这不是真的
oh, this is not happening
老天
oh, man
你们干嘛？
what are you guys doing?
我嘴唇麻了
I can't feel my lip
糟糕
oh, shit
老天
Man
嘿K
Hey. Hey
住手
Hey, stop that
把他的腿绑起来
Hog-tie him, boys
-逮住他这个大猪头
-你干嘛？
-Get him, that big old Bocephus of a man.
-Hey, what are you doing?
把他绑好！这下大也没用了吧
cinch him up good.
You ain't so big now, are you?
住手
Hey. Hey, stop that
每晚，年复一年
Every night, year after year...
你们其中一个警卫
把我们锁在这些箱子里
...one of you guards
locks us up in these boxes
我特此声明，先生K够了！
well, I hereby say, sir, enough!
发动火车头
Fire up the iron horse, boys
-金发男？
-我叫嘉地雅
-Hey, blondie?
-Name's Jedediah
嘉地雅，停住火车
All right, Jedediah. Stop the train, please
-我无能为力，卧轨男
-这是怎么回事？
-That's a big no-can-do, cracker Jack.
-what's going on here, huh?
-有人得受到惩罚
-为什么？
-Somebody's gotta pay.
-Pay for what?
我不知道，就是惩罚！
别叫了，冷静接受惩罚吧
I don't know. Just pay. Now, stop whining
and just take it like a man
说真的，快停住火车
Seriously, stop the train
-好吧，停住火车
-谢谢
-All right, stop the train.
-Thank you
现在全速前进压烂他
Now fulI speed ahead and ram him!
把他的头压个稀巴烂
Split his head like a watermelon!
拜托！
For crying out loud
真是够了
All right, that's enough
有状况！
we got a breach
（巨人逃走了）
我逮到他了
I got him. I got him. I got him, guys.
I got him--
-老天
-准备投石器
-oh, my....
-Prepare the catapults
屋大维，等等，这不是你的战场
这巨人在我们的土地上
octavius, hold on. This ain't your fight.
This here giant's on our land
小家伙，小嘉？
Hey, little guy. Jed? Yeah
我不是巨人，好吗？我身材中等
Sorry, look. I just-- I'm not a giant.
I'm just an average-sized--
别一副高高在上的样子！
Don't tALk down to me
我不是巨人，是你们太小了
I'm not a giant, guys. All right?
You guys are really little
我们也许小，心却很大
we may be small,
but our hearts are large...
这是比喻性的说法
...metaphorically speaking
我只是说你们是很迷你
Don't take that wrong.
I'm saying you're miniatures
安静！罗马帝国无所不知
Silence! The Roman Empire
knows no boundaries
-别那么做，孩子
-怎么做？
-Don't you do it, son.
-Do what?
-屋大维！
-别做什么？
-octavius.
-Don't do what?
-展开攻击！
-不要
-Unleash hell!
-Don't--
上来，孩子
climb aboard, boy
握紧我的手，孩子
Take the hand, son
上马
onboard
是啊，快逃吧！听见没？
That's right. You better run, boy.
You hear Jedediah?
那个八字胡男
他没办法永远保护你的
That mustachioed horseman ain't ALways
gonna be there to protect you, you hear me?
-谢谢你
-别客气
-Thank you.
-Not at all
西奥多罗斯福
Theodore Roosevelt,
26th president...
美国第26任总统，为您效劳
...of these United States of America
at your service
我是赖瑞达理，新进夜班警卫
okay. I'm Larry Daley,
the new night guard
幸会，劳伦斯达理
不过请恕我失礼
Pleasure to me you, Lawrence Daley.
You'll have to excuse me, though
猎杀正在进行
The hunt is afoot
进行猎杀
Hunt's afoot
总统先生，我能问你一些事吗？
Excuse me, Mr. President.
could I ask you something?
可以，不过就一个问题
-Yes, but just one question.
-All right
为什么？这是阿拉丁神灯吗？
okay, why? Is it just some, like,
three-wishes kind of deAL, or--?
不是的
自己才是生存的关键
Not at all. Self-reliance
is the key to a vigorous life
人要向自己的内心寻求解答
我能帮得上什么忙？
A man must look inward to find
his own answers. How can I be of help?
我不知该怎么说，请别误会
I don't really know how to put this,
and please don't take it the wrong way...
不过博物馆里的东西
不是应该K
...but isn't everything in this museum
supposed to be, you know...
一片死寂？
-...dead?
-Dead?
-对
-跟我来
-Yeah.
-Follow me
随你叫吧，法老王
Yell all you want, pharaoh
你待54年了，今晚出不去的
You've been in there 54 years.
You're not getting out tonight
那是一切混乱的根源
There's the source of all this commotion
阿卡曼拉刻写板
The Tablet of Ahkmenrah
1952年尼罗河探险后被送到此
Arrived here in 1 952
from the Nile expedition
就在当晚
博物馆里的一切都活了过来
on that night,
everything in this museum came to life
之后每晚也都如此
And every night since
博物馆里的一切每晚都复活？
So everything in the museum
comes to life every night?
没错
Exactly
那我该做些什么？
And I'm supposed to do what?
你是守夜者，劳伦斯
这机构里最值得尊敬的职位
You're the night watchman, Lawrence.
A venerable position in this institution
-走吧
-好了，这是不可能的
-come on, lad.
-All right. okay. This is impossible
没有不可能的事，梦想也能成真
Nothing's impossible.
If it can be dreamed, it can be done
所以巨大的胡狼神瞪着你，别看他
Hence the 20-foot jackAL staring at you.
Don't make eye contact
你的工作是确保大家待在博物馆
Your job is to make sure that everyone
stays inside the museum...
当太阳出来，要是有人在外面
...because if the sun rises
and anyone's on the outside...
我们就会化为尘埃
...we turn to dust
-尘埃？
-尘埃
-You turn to dust?
-Dust
-真的？
-真的
-Really?
-Really
天快亮了，我帮你恢复秩序吧
Now, it's ALmost dawn.
I shall help you restore order tonight
不过这是我最后一次这么做
明白吗？
But mark my words, it's the last time
I shall ever do so. Is that clear?
明白，我想是吧
我想我不K
Yeah. I mean-- I mean, I guess. I don't...
别唠叨，明白还是不明白？
Stop babbling, boy! Yes or no?
-明白
-很好
-Yes.
-Good
我们动身吧
Let's ride
好，爬虫动物厅很安全
All right. So the Hall of Reptiles is secure
你在找什么？
what are you looking at?
我在K追踪
I'm tracking, dear boy
有个人必须要追踪
欢迎来到这个大家庭
Man's got to track.
welcome to the family, Lawrence
明晚见了
See you tomorrow night
说真的，我怀疑我会再来
Actually, I gotta be honest.
I don't think I'm coming back
什么？你才刚开始呢
what? You've only just begun
这不是我想要的
Yeah, well, this is not exactly what I--
-劳伦斯？
-是
-Lawrence?
-Yeah?
你之前是做什么的？
what did you do
before you took this post?
很多，我发明过“啪哒弹指器”
well, I've done a lot of different things.
I invented this thing called the Snapper
你也放弃发明了？
Did you give up on that as well?
不，我只是碰上了一些障碍
你听说过“拍掌器”吗？
No, I just hit a few roadblocks.
You might have heard of The clapper?
-劳伦斯？
-是，先生
-Lawrence.
-Yes, sir?
有些英雄造时势
有些时势造英雄
Some men are born great.
others have greatness thrust upon them
对你来说，这正是你的时机
For you, this is that very moment
妙啊！唬到你了，孩子
Bully. Got you, boy
是啊，你是唬到我了
Yeah. You got me
跟你的小小朋友打招呼吧
Say hello to your little friend
-你干嘛？
-放我下来
-what are you doing?
-Put me down
我不喜欢被人抓着
I don't like to be manhandled
-冷静点
-这感觉很不好
-Just cALm down, Jed.
-It doesn't feel good
-让我觉得自己渺小又无力
-说完没？
-It makes me feel small and powerless.
-You done?
我要射你的眼睛
射瞎你的狗眼
I'm gonna shoot you in your dang eye.
In your dadgum eye
继续射啊，根本不会有事
Yeah, keep shooting.
Nothing's gonna happen
你现在知道我丢脸的地方了
Now you know my shame
嘉地雅无能，他的枪没用
Jedediah's impotent rage.
His guns don't fire. Take me away
还没完呢，你等着瞧吧
This ain't over.
You ain't seen the last of me
我不想听了，好吗？
I don't wanna hear it, okay?
蹲下！
Duck!
个子越大，摔的越重
The bigger they are, the harder they fall
这工作给的钟点费也太低了
This is not worth 1 1 .50 an hour
巨人好怕，有更大的东西在跑耶
Look, the giant's scared.
There's a bigger giant running around
喂！
Hello
赖瑞？
Larry?
别那样，我们年纪大不经吓
oh, don't do that.
we're too old for surprises
我以为你们喜欢惊喜
像你们给我的惊喜
Really? I thought you liked surprises.
Like how you surprised me...
像博物馆的东西晚上都会活过来
...with the fact everything in
the museum comes to life at night
真是太有趣了
That little sweetheart
你根本不会相信我们的
we wanted to tell you.
You never would have believed us
-你们知道我昨晚怎么过的吗？
-什么？
-You have any idea what I've been through?
-what?
-你们知道我昨晚怎么过的吗？
-安静点，胆小鬼
-You have any idea what I've been through?
-Keep a lid on it, butterscotch
听着，我不知道那是真的假的
但我没同意要参一脚
I don't know if what happened last night
was reAL, but I didn't sign up for this
我只是需要一份正常工作
没生命危险，又能应付开销
I just need a regular job that
is not life-threatening and pays my bills
所以感谢你们
我把制服留在办公室里
So thank you very much
and I left my uniform in the office...
-我把制服留在办公室，再见
-赖瑞！
-...and I will be seeing you.
-Larry!
-爸？
-嘿
-Dad?
-Hey
小子，你来这干嘛？
Hey, buddy.
what are you guys doing here?
雅莉要去法院
所以我带大人物先生去学校
oh, Erica had to be in court early,
so I'm taking Mr. Big Stuff here to school
他想来看你的新工作
But he wanted to swing by,
see you in the new job
你在这里工作真棒
It's so awesome
that you're working here
小家伙，要不要进去看看？
Hey, Niko, you wanna take
a little look-a-doo inside?
也许你爸会给你贵宝级的导览
Maybe your dad will give you a vIP tour
其实，我们今天早上很忙
You know what?
we're pretty slammed this morning
不过尼克，我保证
我很快就带你来参观，好吗？
Yeah, but Nicky, I promise,
I'll show you around soon, okay? DeAL?
-好
-很好
-DeAL.
-All right
-拜，爸爸
-拜
-Bye, Dad.
-Bye
-我爱你
-我也爱你，小乖
-Love you.
-Love you too, buddy
-再见
-好
Bye, now. All right
赖瑞
Hey, Larry
我就再试一个晚上吧
So I was thinking
maybe I'll give it one more night
我很高兴，欢迎回来
I'm glad you came around.
welcome back
你！晚班警卫，马上过来
You. New night guard, here, now
-怎么了？
-“怎么了？”
-what's up?
-“what's up?”
跟我走，我带你去看，  “怎么了先生”
oh, well, take a wALk with me
and I'll show you, Mr. “what's up?”
来
come on
麻烦你解释这是怎么回事？
So would you kindly do me the favor
of explaining this?
好，这个嘛
okay. I'm guessing--
我猜，我也只是猜想啦
And I'm just spitbALling here,
but looks like that Roman dude got cocky...
不过我想
罗马人太狂妄，跑进大西部
...and climbed over into the wild west
牛仔知道罗马人想夺取他的地盘
And the cowboy knows Roman dude
wants to take over his territory...
所以就把他架上示众O
...so he rounded up a posse
and put him in the stockade
笑吧，搞笑夜班警卫
“Let's all laugh at me,
the comedy night guard.”
答案是不对
“No” is the answer
我这是挖苦你的烂幽默感
Sarcasm back at you,
with your humor box
我没笑
I wasn't laughing. Pretending to laugh...
我是假笑，如果那是你想要的
你想比幽默
...if that's what you want,
some sort of battle of humor
是吗？
Do you?
不是的
No
我并不想比幽默
I don't want--
No, I don't want a battle of humor
当然，因为那样你会一败涂地
No, you don't,
because it would be a bloodbath
大角山战役并不好笑
Nothing funny about Little Bighorn
我认为那跟追星族一样可笑
No. I find it about as funny
as a “fancist.”
这不好笑，好吗？
我不会容许这么过份的K
It's not funny. okay? And I will not
stand for this type of blatant...
要是我没说清楚，告诉我
If I'm not clear, tell me
我说清楚了吗？
Am I clear?
是啊
-Yeah.
-Yeah?
克西？
Hey, cecil?
那本指令手册你有备份吗？
You got an extra copy
of that instruction manuAL?
-恐怕没有
-我告诉你该怎么做吧
oh, no. I'm afraid not, Larry.
Listen, I'll tell you what you do
去看一些书，重温历史
Read some books.
Brush up on your history
我刚来时，那对我助益很大
Helped me a lot when I first started out
这间博物馆是献给那个骑马的人
This museum was originally dedicated
to that man on the horse up there...
西奥多罗斯福
...President Theodore Roosevelt
他喜爱历史
也相信人越明t过去
He absolutely loved history and believed
that the more you know about the past...
就更能准备好迎接未来
...the better prepared you are
for the future
好了，谁能告诉我这间是什么？
okay, kids. who can tell me
what this room's called?
很好，非洲哺乳动物陈列室
very good. The Hall of African MammALs
这是丛林之王，狮子
Right here we have the king of the jungle,
the lion
上面是我最喜欢的动物之一
僧帽猴
Up ahead is one of my favorite creatures
in the whole museum, the capuchin monkey
一种具有高度智慧的灵长类
以其仁慈慷慨的天性闻名
A highly intelligent primate
known for its loving and generous nature
抱歉？
Excuse me?
我只是觉得K
I just thought that was...
我只是有同感的笑出来
I just was laughing in agreement
快乐的猴子
Happy monkey
好了，孩子们，往这边来
All right, kids. This way
我告诉你
我才不买帐
Let me tell you something.
I'm not buying it
你骗的了小孩，骗不了我
你骗不倒我的
You might have them fooled,
you might have the kids fooled. Not me
等着瞧吧，好戏即将登场
can't get past me.
There's a storm coming, buddy
好戏即将登场
There's a storm coming
历史上最有名的追踪者之一
莎卡佳哩
one of the most famous trackers
in history, Sakagawea was the woman...
她引领路易斯和克拉克
找到太平洋
...who led Lewis and clark on
their expedition to find the Pacific ocean
你们也许听过这句话
“坐而言不如起而行”
You guys have heard the saying,
“Actions speak louder than words.”
但他们写K
And yet they wrote--
-是的，达理先生？
-她是聋子吗？
-Yes, Mr. Daley?
-Yes. was she deaf?
聋？不，她不是
was she deaf? No. She was not.
But she--
因为她看来有点K
没反应
Yeah, because-- Just-- She does seem
a little bit sort of unresponsive
那是因为她是一尊雕像
That's because she's a statue
等我一下
去看看她吧，她很酷的
Kids, could you give me one sec?
Go check her out. She's really cool
-你这是干嘛？
-既然我每晚都要待在这
-what are you doing?
-I'm gonna be here every night
我想认识我所守卫的东西
I wanted to learn a little bit more
about what I'm guarding
事实上，我有一堆问题
Actually, I've got a bunch of questions
等你休息，我能请你喝咖啡吗？
Maybe when you have a break,
could I buy you a cup of coffee?
喝咖啡？
A cup of coffee?
对，纯粹是同事对同事
Yeah, I mean, just purely a, you know...
资讯交流那类的咖啡
...colleague-to-colleague,
information-download sort of coffee
过二十分钟再见
I finish in 20 minutes.
I'll meet you outside
-谢谢你
-不客气
-Thank you.
-You're welcome
-希望你有个好的K
-好了，孩子们
-And have a good rest of your--
-All right. okay, kids
她很厉害
It was incredible what she did
她引领这些人跋山涉水
She literally led these men
across rivers, up mountains...
她身上还背着孩子
她是终极的职业母亲
...all with her newborn baby on her back.
She was the ultimate working mother
你真是莎卡假哩专家
wow, you are quite
the Sakagawean expert
-是莎卡佳哩
-莎卡佳哩？
-Sakagawean.
-Sakagawean?
这是自然的
我这篇论文准备了四年
Yeah. I should be, I've been writing
my dissertation on her for four years
四年写一篇论文？
是我铁定会抓狂
You've been working on one paper
for four years? That would drive me crazy
其实那比较像是一本九百页的书
Actually, it's more like a 900-page book
你呢？你从小就立志当警卫？
So, what's your story? Have you
ALways wanted to be a security guard?
-我不是故意K
-不、不
-oh, I didn't mean to--
-No, no, no
我离婚了，还有个十岁大的儿子
No, I'm divorced
and I have a 1 0-year-old son...
我需要更稳定一点的生活
...so I needed to find
a more steady situation
懂了，你想知道馆里什么事？
Got it. So, what can I tell you
about the museum?
匈奴王阿提拉
他是怎么搞的？
okay, Attila the Hun.
what is that guy's problem?
他是唯一威胁过罗马帝国的人
Attila was considered the only
genuine threat to the Roman Empire
人称“恐怖魔王”
Known as the 'Scourge of God' ...
阿提拉和他的手下
常将无助的受害者五马分尸
...Attila and his Huns would often
tear off the limbs of their helpless victims
他以迷信著称
Attila was famous
for his superstitious beliefs
身旁围绕着巫师和术士
He surrounded himself with a phALanx
of sorcerers and magicians...
他们以黑魔法迷惑指使他
...who advised and mystified him
with their dark arts
（复活岛）
（大西部驿马车）
（罗马战争策略）
赖瑞？
Larry?
我只想祝你好运
Just wanted to say good Iuck, son
还有再见，这是我们最后一晚
And goodbye.
we're clocking out for the last time
到了波卡，来找我们
If you're ever in Boca, look us up
你们要出城？
万一这一切不顺利呢？
wait, you guys are going out of town?
what if this doesn't work out?
你这么聪明，一定没问题的
Smart fellow like you? You'll be fine
打个电话就能找到我们
送我们出去吧
Yeah. we'll just be a phone call away.
come on, wALk us out
你们先走
You fellas go ahead
我需要独处一下
I need a moment
他很感伤
这房里有许多回忆
He's very emotionAL.
A lot of memories in this room
好好玩吧，大个子
Go crazy, big guy
你们好
Hey, guys
找火？
Quest for fire...
搞定
自己找乐子吧
...over. Knock yourselves out
早安，笨笨
Morning, dum-dum
我不笨笨，你笨笨
你有糖糖吗？
Me no dum-dum. You dum-dum.
You bring me gum-gum?
有，大头呆，很多糖糖
Yes, I did, fathead.
Lots and lots of gum-gum
什么？
我听不见，玻璃挡住了
what's that?
I can't hear you through the glass
抱歉
Sorry
用力拉！
Heave
Heave. Heave
怎么回事？
Hey, what's going on over here?
不扩张，就得死
we expand or we die
用力拉！
Heave
数到三
-Heave.
-on the count of three...
就炸翻这个蚁丘
...you blow this anthill to kingdom come
嘉地雅，住手
-And a one and a two--
-Hey, Jed. Stop that
别这样，你炸山
只是在炸墙
No, no. You blow a hole in your mountain,
all you're gonna hit is a wall
别管闲事，巨怪
我们要建铁道，要炸山洞
Step aside, Gigantor. we got us a railroad
to build. we're blowing a hole in that thing
第一，别再叫我什么巨怪了
okay, first of all, enough with
the Gigantor giant stuff, okay?
-我只想停止这一切
-我们就是要炸
-I'm just trying to close up shop.
-we're gonna blow it anyway. And a three!
是啊，碰，了不起
你干嘛？
Yeah. what are you doing?
这像干嘛？这是天命
what's it look like we're doing?
It's manifest destiny
你无法与之抗衡，我也一样
再多用点火药
You can't fight it and neither can I.
Go! More dynamite
-对，全用了
-好啊，很好
-Yeah, use it all.
-All right. okay
听着，屋大尾？你得停止那样
Listen, “octavus”? You gotta stop that
我叫屋大维，赖皮
It's octavius, mary
好吧，来，事情就会变成这样
okay, you know what? Fine. Great.
Here you go. This is what happens
你不能这样，我是罗马将军
-You cannot do this. I am a Roman generAL.
-Sorry
-我有权利
-还有你
-I have rights.
-And you
-嘿，不，放我下来
-继续攻
-Hey, no! Put me down!
-Keep heaving, men
我会回来的，我发誓
You can't stop progress!
我们要谈一谈
we're gonna have a little tALk, okay?
我说过我不喜欢被人抓着
I told you, I don't like to be manhandled
不，我要抓着你
No, I will manhandle you, Jedediah.
Now, listen, guys
你们到底是怎样？
为什么老处不来？
what is your problem, huh?
why can't you just get ALong?
我们是男人，我们战斗，就这样
Look, we're men. we fight, okay?
That's what we do
我们都这样杀时间
It's kind of how we pass the time
你是巨人、怪胎
你没办法了解的
You're, like, a giant. A freak, if you will.
we can't expect you to understand that
空间很大，你们不用腻在一起
You got the whole room to run around in.
You don't have to be near each other
-什么？你是说
-你要让我们出去？
-what, you mean...?
-You're gonna let us out?
四处闲逛？
what, and just roam free?
有可能，只要你们保证不乱来
Yeah. Yeah, I might,
if you promise to behave
那表示没火花、没爆炸
That means no fireballs,
no explosions, okay?
我敢起誓，主人
You have my word, my liege
是啊，没问题，巨怪
Yeah, no problemo, Gigantor
首先，我的名字叫赖瑞
阿嘉
My name's Larry, first of all. okay, Jed?
我叫你阿嘉，不叫你小人
So I call you Jed.
I don't call you Tiny, right?
那是什么意思？
what's that supposed to mean?
-小鬼头，如何？
-我不喜欢，我很受伤
-“Hey, Teeny.” How does that sound?
-I don't like it. It hurts my feelings
“巨怪”也让我觉得像怪胎
“Gigantor” makes me feel
like some sort of freak, so...
我不会那样，我就叫你赖瑞
I don't. I just call you Larry
少谄媚了
Don't be a kiss-ass, okay?
我现在信任你们
Look, I'm trusting you guys, all right?
你们要是不听我的话
就会跟小马雅人一样
If you don't do what I say,
you can end up like the Mayan world there
被关起来，你们看
Locked up. Take a look
-他们看来高兴吗？
-不
-Do they look happy?
-No
他们看来很难过
They look sad
因为他们不能为所欲为
They can't do what they wanna do.
Now, I'm letting you guys...
现在我给你们一点自由
别让我失望
...have a little bit of leash here.
Don't choke me with it, okay?
我得走了，好好相处，好吗？
好，谢了
I gotta run. You guys play nice, okay?
okay. Good. Thanks
笨笨，糖糖好吃吗？
Hey, how's that gum treating you,
dum-dum?
好吃
Good
德克斯，我要锁了，要进来吗？
oh, hey, Dexter.
I'm just locking up. You want in?
很好
Yeah?
好吧
All right
什么？你拿了我的钥匙？
what's that? You got my keys?
我可不这么想
I don't think so
看来老赖瑞骗过小德克斯了
Looks like Uncle Larry pulled a fast one
on little Dexie
那是给小宝宝玩的玩具钥匙
Those are baby keys for a little baby
好好玩吧，小猴子
Have fun with your baby keys,
little baby monkey
也许明天我会带纸尿布给你
你可以拿来便便
Tomorrow I'll bring you a little baby diapy
so you can go poo-poo in it
我会搔搔你的痒
因为你是可爱的小猴子
I'll give you a tickle
because you're a cute baby
赖瑞叔叔骗你，你要哭整晚吗？
while you cry all night long
about how Uncle Larry fooled you, huh?
我说过好戏即将登场
I told you there was a storm coming
-你好，泰迪
-劳伦斯
-Hey, Teddy.
-Lawrence
你这个没礼貌的小子
我就知道你会回来
You impertinent pup.
I knew you'd come back
-你看来身负重任
-我准备再试一次
-You look like a man on a mission.
-Yeah, I'm gonna give it another shot
-你
-什么K
-You...?
-what?
-你在打量她？
-真敢说
-You checking her out?
-The nerve
打量，我没听过这种说法
checking her out.
I've never heard of such a thing
不，我是说，她很美
No, no, no. I'm just-- I mean
because, you know, she's very beautiful
-美？
-是啊
-Beautiful?
-Yeah
-我认为是个俊俏的女人
-是啊
-Rather handsome woman, I suppose.
-Yeah
也许你该去跟她说个话
I don't know,
maybe you should go tALk to her
是啊！
祝福你，小子
-Indeed. Bless you, lad.
-Yeah. All right
-继续加油吧
-好，再见
-carry on.
-Good. See you
我K
I...
嘿，嗨
Hey, hi
不，没关系
没关系，你们会说英文吗？
No! It's okay!
It's okay. You guys speak English?
不会？
No?
是啊，我不知道那是什么意思
Right. I don't know what that means...
不过我知道我们一开始就没搞好
但是K
...and I know that you and I got off
on the wrong foot last night, but...
有只小鸟告诉我，有人喜欢
...a little birdie told me
that somebody likes...
魔法
...magic
-魔法？
-魔法
-Magic?
-Magic
巫术
Sorcery
Ah, sorcer--
对，幻术
Yes. llIusion
大家都喜欢魔法
Everybody likes magic
还有花，人们都喜欢花
And flowers. People like flowers
那些是给你的
There you go. Those are for you
人们还喜欢什么？钱
You know what else people like?
Money
无所不能的金钱
但金钱有时候会K
The ALmighty dollar, right?
But money can sometimes...
不见
...disappear
至少我是这么K
At least that's what I...
听说的
...hear
难怪你不懂我的话，你耳里有钱
No wonder you can't understand me.
You got a coin in your ear
你们看，有人需要手帕吗？
check this out. Anybody need a hanky?
我不建议拿这条小手帕
因为这顽皮的家伙
well, I wouldn't suggest this little
feller because he has a nasty habit...
会凭空消失
...of vanishing...
不要，那会穿帮K
...into thin air!
别五马分尸，各位
No, no. Don't. That defeats the-- Don't!
拜托，别五马分尸
Not the limbs. Guys, please,
do not tear the limbs
蔻蒂兹，对吧？
cortes, right?
怎么会？
How?
想都别想
You! Don't even think about it.
Don't you--
德克斯
Dexter!
拜托你们
come on, guys!
喂，你们
Hey, guys!
嘿，两位K
Hey, guys. Hey, guys!
抱歉，怎么回事？
Sorry. what's going on?
what happened here?
你们在干嘛？
我们不是讲好了？
I thought we had a deAL
我们永远无法忍受这些小丑
we will never coexist
with these buffoons
承诺已成过去，小赖
we're past words, Laredo
该让手上的家伙说话了
Now it's time to let Smith & wesson
do the tALking!
那玩意根本没用
Those guns don't even work
是吗？你看着
They don't? Take a look at this
德克斯！
Dexter!
为什么？
why?
德克斯
Ho! Dexter
你无路可逃了，小毛猴
End of the line, cool breeze
无路可逃
End of the line
我可不是闹着玩的
I am not playing games here
快给我
Just hand them over
小心，很好，德克斯
Easy. That's it, Dexter
慢慢来，就是这样
Nice and easy, Dex. That's it
老天，你干嘛打猴子？
Good Lord, Lawrence!
why are you slapping a monkey?
这家伙一直惹我，我受够了
Teddy, this guy's been pushing me,
and I'm sick of it!
胡说，这小家伙是你的远亲
Poppycock. This little creature is
your primate brother
没有他，就没有我们
without him, there's no us
你得了狂犬病啦？
Are you rabid?
把泡泡擦干净
wipe that off
你得对这小家伙展现爱和尊重
You have to deAL with this creature
with love and respect
朋友，可以把钥匙给我吗？
May I have the keys, dear friend?
-谢谢
-劳伦斯？
Thank you. Lawrence?
你似乎很清楚该怎么做
well, you know what?You seem to know what you're doing
所以我就让你接手
so I'm gonna let you take over
你不能现在就举白旗
No, no. My dear boy, you can't put up
the white flag now
博物馆正濒临无政府状态
The museum is on the verge
of totAL anarchy
我试过了，我今晚回来了
I tried! I came back tonight,
didn't I?
就一晚，我也建不好巴拿马运河
Tried? That was one night. I didn't build
the Panama canAL in one day
很好，但这是史上最荒谬的工作
That's great, but I'm dealing with
the most ridiculous job in history
有些英雄造时势
Some men are born great, Lawrence--
是，我知道，泰迪
有些时势造英雄
Yeah, I know. others have
greatness thrust upon them
你昨晚就说过那句话了
You hit me with that chestnut
last night
不过不是每个人都是英雄
The thing is, not everyone is great
有些人只是普通人
That's the problem.
Some of us are just ordinary
你不是，别再顾影自怜了
No, you're not, Lawrence.
Stop wallowing in self-pity
每个伟大的旅程
都是由第一步开始
Every journey begins with a footstep
要是你能教导居民和平相处
他们就不用被关起来了
Teach the inhabitants to get ALong,
they wouldn't need to be locked up
-夜复一夜的
-这话出自花五十年偷看女人
That means a lot coming from a guy
who's spent the last 50 years...
却不敢开口的人口中，还真有用
...spying on a girl he's never even
tALked to
我本来要去跟她说话的，拜托
I was going to make contact.
Lawrence, please
我受够了，好吗？
I'm done, all right?
不，笨龙
No, Rexy! No!
不！
oh, no
好吧
All right
没人会再来这了
何况我二年级就来过了
No one comes here anymore. Besides,
I took this tour in second grade, Daley
我爸会给我们私人导览的
I'm telling you,
my dad's gonna hook us up
-达理先生？
-是
-Mr. Daley?
-Yeah?
-泡沫
-是啊，我知道
-Foam.
-Yes, I know
在尼安德塔人展示区里！
In the NeanderthAL display
昨天晚上
灭火器出了点状况
There was an incident last night
with the fire extinguisher
我正要去清理
I was on my way to go clean it up
不用麻烦，你被炒了
okay, don't bother. You're fired
今天没得参观了
I don't think we're getting a tour today
你爸刚被炒了
Your dad just got canned, dude
抱歉
Excuse me?
麦菲先生？
Mr. McPhee?
抱歉，麦菲先生？
Excuse me, Mr. McPhee?
我能跟你谈一谈吗？
can I tALk to you about this, please?
-先生？
-干嘛？
-Sir?
-what?
我错了，但我现在知道该怎么做了
I know I screwed up, but I finally
understand how to do this job
-你显然是不知道
-我本来不知，但现在知道了
-You obviously don't.
-No, I didn't, but now I do
-真的，麦菲先生
-博士
-Really, Mr. McPhee--
-Doctor
麦菲博士
Dr. McPhee
你能再给我一个晚上吗？
can you please give me one more night?
-就再一晚
-好，谢谢
-one more night.
-okay, thank you
要是你当班之后
And if anything is the tiniest...
有任何事发生
...after your shift:
因为K
Because...
-我t
-好吗？
-Got it.
-okay?
骗我一次，是我丢脸
骗我两次
Fool me once, shame on you.
Fool me twice...
是我丢脸K我丢脸
Shame on me. Fool me--
Shame on me
-你
-骗我两次，我t
-You.
-Fool me twice.... Got it
-接不接受随你
-好，谢谢
-Take it or leave it.
-okay. Thank you
-嘿
-Hey.
-Hey
-怎么了？
-也许你该去问尼克
-what's wrong?
-Maybe you should ask Nicky
小子，怎么回事？
Hey, buddy. what's going on?
你被炒了
You got fired
什么？我并没有被炒啊
what are you tALking about?
I didn't get fired
我今早去了博物馆
你老板对你大吼
I came to the museum this morning.
I saw your boss yelling at you
你怎么没告诉我？
一切都没事
why didn't you tell me?
Everything's fine
没事，我们只是有点误会
we just had a little misunderstanding
为什么？
why?
很难解释，我是说
你不会相信K
It's hard to explain.
I mean, you wouldn't bel--
这样吧，我就让你见识一下
You know what? Let me show you
-见识什么？
-跟我一起去上班
-Show me what?
-come to work with me tonight
赖瑞？
Larry?
我能跟你谈一谈吗？
can I tALk to you for a second?
我有麻烦吗？
Am I in trouble?
赖瑞，你在干嘛？
Larry, what are you doing?
我想让他看看我的工作
I just wanna show him what I do.
That's all
我很高兴你想和他分享，可是
I love that you wanna share that
with him, but I gotta tell you...
我不认为尼克能再次承受失望
...I don't think Nicky has any room
in his heart for more disappointment
他不会失望的
He won't be disappointed
赖瑞
Larry
他不会失望的
He won't be disappointed
在警卫室等到大家离开
Listen, hang out in the security
office till everyone's gone
-之后我就会来找你，好吗？
-好
Then I'm gonna come get you.
All right?
小姐？我得请你离开本馆
Hey, miss? I'm gonna have to ask you
to vacate the premises
你好
-Hey there.
-Hey
-很棒的沉思之地
-是啊
-Good place to think, huh?
-Yeah. Definitely
今晚没约会啊？
So no big plans tonight?
我不大喜欢约会
Yeah, no, I'm not really
a big-plan person
我喜欢跟已死之人相处
I prefer hanging out with people
who are dead for 200 years
活人令我困惑
It's the live ones that throw me
但说真的，你得走了
That's cool. Seriously though,
you do have to leave
-认真的？
-抱歉，博物馆的规定
-Seriously?
-Yeah, sorry. It's museum rules
我们要把一切都锁起来
we're sort of locking everything up
你很认真执行你的工作
You're really taking your job seriously
我一戴上领带，就很认真
You know, once I clip on the tie,
I'm all business
-我明白了
-好
-I get it.
-Yeah
论文进度如何？
How's that dissertation coming?
我遇上瓶颈了
研究只能让我到此为止
I've hit a dead end. I mean,
research can only get me so far
我永远不会认识真正的她
I'm never gonna know
who she really was
我想我该研究别的主题了
So I think it's time that I move on
to another subject
我就让你继续工作吧
I'll let you get back to work
-晚安，赖瑞
-好K
-Good night, Larry.
-Yeah, okay
晚安
Night
嘿
Hey
贝嘉
Rebecca!
-嘿，贝嘉
-嘿
-Hey, Rebecca.
-Hey
我不认为你该放弃你的论文
Hey. Listen, I don't think you should
give up on your paper
好吧，为什么？
okay. why?
这听起来可能有点疯狂
All right, look, this is gonna
sound crazy, all right?
听起来真的很疯狂
I mean, it's gonna sound, like,
really, really crazy
-好吧
-我是说超疯狂的疯狂
-okay.
-No, I mean insanely crazy
-我能接受
-好
-I can handle it.
-okay
你知道在某些博物馆里
历史会栩栩如生
You know how they say in certain
museums, history comes alive?
-是啊
-在这间博物馆里
-Yeah.
-In this museum...
一切真的活了过来
...it actually does
你在胡说什么？
what are you tALking about?
这馆内的一切在晚上都会活过来
Everything in this museum
comes to life at night
-真的？
-是真的，我没骗你
-Really?
-Yeah, really. I'm not kidding you
你知道阿卡曼拉刻写板吧？
You know that tablet?
The Tablet of Ahkmenrah?
它让一切活过来
It actually brings things to life.
It's like some ancient spell
自它来了以后，一切都活了过来
Since the '50s, every night
everything's been coming to life
泰迪罗斯福跟我说的
真的！那只猴子，德克斯？
Teddy Roosevelt told me. Seriously.
The monkey, Dexter? The cute little--
-他是什么来着？僧帽猴
-僧帽猴
-what is he?
-capuchin
他咬了我的鼻子
还在我身上撒了尿
A capuchin. Right. The capuchin.
He urinated on me and bit my nose
莎卡佳哩在柜子里，每晚都复活
And Sakagawea is in her case,
alive every night...
聆听路易斯和克拉克吵嘴
...just listening to Lewis and clark
argue
所以你要是想了解她
So if you really wanna get inside
her head...
我能帮你安排
...I can hook that up
真是太棒了
That's cool
是啊，是很棒，棒呆了
Yeah, it's cool. It's freaking awesome
嘲笑历史学者
Make fun of the history geek
-不是的，贝嘉
-晚安，赖瑞
-No. Rebecca!
-Good night, Larry
我不是在嘲笑你，贝嘉？
No, I'm not making fun of you.
Rebecca
-馆内的最佳座位
-怎么回事？
-Here you go. Best seat in the house.
-what's going on?
-用说的你不会信，我让你自己看
-什么？
If I told you, you'd think I'm crazy.
I'm gonna show you
你再过20秒就会看到了
-what?
-You'll see in about 20 seconds
-你喜欢暴龙吧？
-喜欢
-okay, you like Tyrannosaurus Rex?
-Yeah
我叫他小龙
Yeah? well, I call him Rexy
他就快活过来了，儿子
再过
And he's about to come to life,
Nicholas, in...
五、四、三、二
...five, four, three, two...
-爸？
-等一下
-Dad?
-Hang on a sec
跟小龙打声招呼吧
Say hello to Rexy!
爸，你没事吧？
Dad, are you okay?
怪了
This is weird
大家出来啊！
Guys! come on!
太阳下山了
Sundown!
总统，起床了，我要你醒来
Hey, T.R., come on, rise and shine.
Buddy, I need you to wake up
我儿子来了，醒醒啊
come on, my kid is here.
I need you to wake up
德克萨斯？快点，快跑啊
Texas? Texas! come on!
Texas! come on! Get on, Texas!
快跑，德克萨斯
Get on, Texas! Get up
别闹了，好吗？
Just stop, okay?
尼克
我告诉你，那里有个板子
No, Nicky, I'm telling you,
there's this tablet, okay?
阿卡曼拉刻写板
called the Tablet of Ahkmenrah.
Every night--
-这下又有个板子了？
-是啊
-Now there's a tablet?
-Yeah, there is
拜托，爸
come on, Dad
跟我来
come on
-它不见了
-什么不见了？
-It's gone.
-what's gone?
板子，我想有人偷走了它
The tablet. I think somebody stole it
是啊
Yeah, right
我不是开玩笑的，儿子
I'm not kidding, Nicky
尼克？
Nicky?
嘿，尼克
Hey, Nicky!
嘿，尼克，你要去哪？
Hey! Hey, Nicky! where are you going?
-回家
-等一下
-Home.
-what? wait a minute
走吧
come on
你们不该在这里的
You guys shouldn't be here
把板子给我们
Give us the tablet, son
等等，尼克，你们在干嘛？
wait a minute, Nicky.
what are you guys doing?
我们不会伤害你，把板子给我们
we're not gonna hurt you.
Give us the tablet
抱歉告诉你这一切，孩子
不过你爸不在这工作，他被炒了
I'm sorry to tell you this, son,
but your dad doesn't work here He got fired this morning
无法胜任
couldn't hack it
爸？你说过你没被炒的
Dad? I thought you said
you weren't fired
他们骗人，这样他们才能偷东西
I did. They're lying,
trying to steAL that thing
把中间那块翻过来，你就明白了
Turn the middle piece,
you'll see what I was tALking about
那是博物馆的财产，孩子
拿给我
That is museum property, son.
Give it back
尼克，相信我，快翻
Nicky, trust me. Just turn it
-把板子给我们
-尼克？
-Give us the tablet!
-Nicky?
相信我
Trust me
尼克？快跑
Nick? Run. Now
给我回来，小鬼
Get back here, kid!
坏主意，赖瑞
Bad idea, Larry
想打架吗？
You wanna dance, hot dog?
You wanna dance?
葛斯，你是老人
我不想伤你
Gus, you're an old man.
I don't wanna hurt you
赖瑞，担任这工作几年下来
我们就明白
You see, Larry, a few years into
the job, the three of us realized that...
我们就像博物馆里的一切
夜里会有新生命
...like everything else in this museum,
we got new life at night
日落到日出，我们都重获新生
Sundown to sunrise,
we felt young again
我没想到有那招
okay. Did not see that coming
让我们重获活力
Gave us an energy boost
我们喜欢夜生活，赖瑞
we love the nightlife, Larry
所以一等他们辞退我们
So when we found out
they were gonna fired us...
我们就得偷走板子
...we had to steAL the tablet
大家都知道你需要钱
Everyone knows you need the money
栽赃在你家的赃物
Add the stuff we planted
in your place...
刚好成了你的罪证
...pretty obvious you committed
the crime
好好照料伤口
Take care of that cut
我们去找那个小鬼吧
come on, guys, let's go find that kid
-祝你好梦，呆头
-不！
-Sweet dreams, cupcake!
-No!
岩石落下技！
Pile driver!
我们去拿板子吧
Let's get our tablet
谢谢，我们就从这里接手
Thank you very much.
we'll take it from here
尼克
Nicky!
刚好，我们正要锁门呢
Just in time, Larry.
we were just locking up
好好睡吧
Sleep tight, hotshot
快去拿值钱的东西吧
Let's grab everything we can fence
我打算要过一段好日子
I don't know about you,
but I'm planning on a long retirement
泰迪！你在的话，我需要你
Teddy! Teddy, if you're out there,
I need you, pAL!
有人叫我吗？
Someone call my name?
西奥多罗斯福，为您效命
Theodore Roosevelt, at your service
泰迪
你能带我们出去吗？
Teddy, can you get us out of here?
做不到，这是你人生的机会
can't do it, man. This is your moment
拜托你少开讲了，我不是你
will you save the lectures, please?
I'm not you. okay?
我没建巴拿马运河，也不是总统
I didn't build the Panama canAL,
I wasn't president of the United States!
我需要帮忙
I need some help. come on
事实上
Actually...
那些事也不是我做的
是泰迪罗斯福做的
...I never did any of those things.
Teddy Roosevelt did
我是模型工厂的产品
I was made in a mannequin factory
in Poughkeepsie
我从未射杀过野兽
I never shot a wild beast
我也没勇气告诉那位女士我爱她
I'm not even brave enough to tell
that beautiful woman I love her
不过你
But you...
你这次得完成这个工作
你不能放弃
...you gotta finish the job this time.
You can't quit
我是蜡做的，劳伦斯
I'm made of wax, Larry
你又是什么做的？
what are you made of?
-等等，那就是你的忠告？
-没错
-wait! That's all you got for me?
-That's it!
这就对了，来吧
That's it. come on
低头！
Duck!
过去
Go over there!
嗨，你好吗？
抱歉打扰你了
Hey. Hi. How you doing?
Sorry to bother you...
不过，你的卫兵
你的胡狼神K
...but your guys there? Your jackAL guys?
你能不能请他们退下？
Do you think you could ask them
to back off, please?
我们不想伤你，但他们不这么想
拜托你快点！
we're not trying to hurt you, they think
we are. could you do it like now?
谢谢你，尼克
Thank you. Nicky
谢了
Thank you
爸？
Dad?
你不会相信这里面有多闷
You would not believe how stuffy
it is in there
-你怎么会说英文？
-我上过剑桥
-How come you speak English?
-I went to cambridge University
你上过剑桥？
You went to cambridge?
我在埃及古物学系作过展示
I was on display
in the Egyptology Department
我是阿卡曼拉
第四王朝的第四任国王
I am Ahkmenrah, fourth king
of the fourth king...
我父亲王国的统治者
...ruler of the land of my fathers
我是赖瑞
I am Larry...
密尔顿之子
...son of Milton...
这是我儿，尼克
...and this is my son, Nick
我们来自布鲁克林
And we hail from Brooklyn
就我啦
他每周三和K
well, I do. I mean, he comes out and
stays with me on wednesdays...
隔周周末跟我住
...and every other weekend
监护权的协议
That was the custody agreement
that we had
赖瑞、尼克，布鲁克林守护者
Larry, Nick, guardians of Brooklyn...
我永远感谢你们
...I am forever in your debt
现在请将刻写板给我
Now bestow the tablet upon me...
好让我重掌我的王国
...so that I may assume command
of my kingdom
好，刻写板，我很乐意
oh, yes. okay, the tablet. I would...
将它返回给你，可是它不在
...love to bestow it upon you,
but we don't actually...
我们手上
...have it
谢了，我会保护他的
Thanks, guys. Don't worry.
I'll watch out for him!
谢谢
Thank you
那是什么？
what is that?
匈奴人
Huns
我得解决这个家伙
I gotta deAL with this guy
抱歉，赖瑞，我会说匈奴话
Pardon me, Larry. I speak Hun
他想把你五马分尸
He says that he wants to rip you apart
又要分尸，我明白
All right. Again with the ripping.
Listen, I understand
我懂了，你想撕扯什么
I get it. Ripping for you....
You want to rip things, okay?
也许是因为很久以前
有人撕扯了你
And I think maybe that's because
somebody ripped you a long time ago
在这里
In here
很久以前
Somebody ripped little...
有人伤了小阿提拉，就在这里
...baby Attila a long time ago,
right here
他们摧毁了某个东西，对吧？
They ripped something out,
didn't they?
他们摧毁了爱
They ripped the love
让你失去了爱
They ripped the love right out of you,
didn't they?
小宝宝孤单待在帐棚里
A little baby all ALone in a tent...
爸爸出门去
...whose daddy went off...
去掠夺某个城镇，或者
...to pillage some town...
去抢某个地方，做他该做的事
...or go and plunder somewhere,
just doing his job
可是谁被扔在家里？
But who was left ALone?
你
You
别压抑，释放出来吧
Let it out. Let it go. Let it go
没事了
It's okay. It's okay
你是下一个
You're next
很好，深呼吸
Good. That's good. Just breathe
赖瑞达理
-Larry Daley.
-Yeah
很好
Good. Yes
是，很好，很好
Yeah. okay. Good, good
好了
大家听着
All right!
I need everybody to listen up!
各位，听我说
Guys! come on!
安静！
Quiet!
我的笨笨有话要说
My dum-dum want to speak
谢谢
Thank you
这位是阿卡曼拉王
Now, this here's King Ahkmenrah
他的板子让各位每晚重获新生
His tablet is what brings you to life
every night
这些夜班老警卫偷走了它
And those old night watchmen?
They stole it
在天亮之前
Now, we need to find those guards
and get the tablet back...
我们得找到这些警卫，拿回板子
...and we need to do it before morning
南北战争士兵！
快去天文馆
civil war guys,
head over to the Planetarium wing
我不记得我探险家朋友的名字了
My explorer friend
whose name escapes me
-是哥伦布
-哥伦布！对，真抱歉
-It's columbus.
-Right, columbus! Right, I'm sorry
你又没挂名牌，哥伦布
带尼安德塔人去搜索
There's no nameplate, so....
columbus, take the NeanderthALs...
无脊椎和爬虫类动物陈列室
...and do a sweep from Invertebrates
all the way through Reptiles
嘉地雅和屋大维
他们的货车在后面，看住它
Jed and octavius, their van's parked
out back. Go take care of it
不要，我不跟穿袍子的人合作
whoa, whoa, whoa, no!
No, sir. I ain't working with toga boy
罗马人单打独斗
Romans work ALone
-那又不会痛，少孩子气了
-会痛啦！
-That didn't hurt. Don't be a baby.
-Yes, it did
少蠢了
come on
那一下比较用力
That was much harder!
两位，拜托
Guys, come on!
阿嘉、屋大维
Jed, octavius
你们的年代虽然差了两千年
Take away the fact you were born
2000 years apart...
但你们并没有那么大的差异
...you guys aren't that different
你们都是伟大的领袖
You're both great leaders
你们都为自己的人民谋福利
对吗？
You just want what's best
for your people, right?
-对
-Yeah.
-Yeah
南北战争的兵士们
civil war dudes
拜托，你们是同胞
别再打斗了
You guys are brothers, for God's sakes.
You gotta stop fighting
北方赢了，奴隶不对，抱歉
North wins. Slavery's bad. Sorry
我并不想毁了你们的幻想
不过南方，你们有艾曼兄弟
Don't wanna burst your bubble.
But, South, you guys get Allman Brothers...
还有房车赛，别激动了
...and NAScAR, so just chill!
听着
没有了刻写板，这一切
Look, without that tablet,
all of this...
夜生活就会划下休止符
...this whole coming-to-life-at-night thing,
it all goes away
我不想那样，但我需要你们帮忙
Now, I don't wanna let that happen,
but I need your help
我们做得到，但我们得齐心合力
we can get this done,
but we gotta do it together
谁要帮我？
So who's with me?
好
Yeah
-谁跟我同一阵线？
-好耶！
-who's with me?
-Yeah!
-好啊
-冲啊！
-Yeah!
-charge!
好耶，我们动手吧
All right! Now, let's do this, people!
还有动物们
And animALs!
还有无脸男们，一起来吧
And weird, faceless puppet creatures.
come on, let's go! Let's do it!
跟我来，各位
come on! Follow me, boys!
吉拉尼莫！
Geronimo!
天哪
oh, jeez
各位，要来软的还是硬的
Now, boys, we can do this the easy way
or the hard way
我想你们是想来硬的
I guess it's gonna be the hard way
我们就快到了
Right, men, we're ALmost there
救救你自己吧
Save yourself!
我不想戒掉你
I ain't quitting you!
葛斯？
Gus?
雷纳？
ReginALd?
两位？你们在哪里？
Fellas, where are you?
兄弟们？
Guys?
我就说嘛，干的好！
That's what I'm tALking about.
Good job, gentlemen
团队合作太棒了
Loving the teamwork!
他们消失了，要怎么找他们？
They've vanished.
How will we find them?
我知道有人能帮忙
来吧
I know someone who can help. come on
小心！
watch out!
莎卡佳尾，或佳哩
有人偷了他的板子
Hey, Sakagawea, or wea. Listen,
I need a favor. Somebody stole his tablet
你能追踪拿走它的人吗？
You think you can track the guys
who took it?
他往东走
不过失控撞车了
He went east
but he lost control and crashed
真厉害，你怎么知道的？
You're amazing. How can you tell that?
他放弃车子
He left the wagon...
跑回去了
...and went back
跑回去？
He went back?
他为什么要回去？
why would he go back?
让开！
Get out of the way!
你救了我
You saved me
你值得我救，亲爱的
You're worth saving, my dear
-这下有问题了
-泰迪，老天
-That's problematic.
-Teddy. oh, man
劳伦斯，别紧张，我是蜡做的
Larry, relax. I'm wax
不过快天亮了
You gotta do something.
Dawn's approaching
馆里大半的东西都在外面乱跑
他拿了我的板子
-HALf the museum's running amuck outside.
-He's got my tablet
走吧，小屋
come on, ockie!
为您效劳，巨怪
At your service, Gigantor!
主人，我们该怎么帮忙？
How can we be of assistance, my liege?
让我想一下
Just give me a second, guys
小龙？
Rexy?
过来，小乖
Here, boy
泰迪，我需要一匹马
Teddy, I need a horse
快去吧
Do it, man
来啊，让我听你吼吧！
-come on, boy! Let me hear you yell!
-Yeah!
这真是梦想成真
Just living the dream, baby!
我爱死这一切了
I'm loving this!
快停住马车
现在！
PulI the stagecoach over now!
这个弯能交给我吗？
can I make this turn up here?
我就当是答应了，坐稳了
I'll take that as a yes. Hang on!
我控制不了它
I can't hold it!
走，我们了结这一切吧
come on, Tex, let's finish this
快啊
come on!
把板子给我
Give me the tablet, cecil!
做不到
can't do it, son
停下
PulI over!
那是不可能的，走吧
It ain't gonna happen. Moving on
快停住，不然我就动手了
Last chance, cecil.
Stop the horses or I will!
他们停不住的
They can't be stopped, Larry
你历史没学好吗？
Don't you know your history?
他们是载运钱财的
他们只听一个秘密指令
These are money carriers. They were trained
not to stop for anything but a secret word
真的吗？你是说像K
Really? You mean a word like...
达科塔！
...“Dakota”?
过去，德克萨斯
come on, Tex
我温习过历史了，感谢指点
I read up on my history.
Thanks for the tip
还有
oh, and by the way...
别在我儿子面前那样对我说话我
...don't ever tALk to me like that
in front of my son
走吧
Moving on
-嘿，匈奴人
-叫阿提拉让他的手下
-Hey, Huns.
-Tell Attila to have his boys...
把他跟其他警卫绑在一起
...take him back.
Put him with the guards
还有，别五马分尸了
oh, and no limb ripping, okay?
等等，别急
不要那么激动
Hey, boy. wait, wait, hold the phone
“马基卡卡”啥意思？
翻译一下，拜托
what's maKeeKaKa mean?
wait. Translation, please
那是在1909年
我沿尚比西河而上
The year was 1 909. I was going up
the Zambezi River in Africa
我们的矮黑人向导用喀嗒声说话
And our river guide was a brilliant Pygmy
who spoke only by clicking
好了
There we are
老天
怎么了？
-oh, boy.
-what is it?
我得把你们弄回博物馆
I gotta get you guys
back to the museum
怎么弄？
How?
阿卡曼拉，我需要你帮忙
Ahkmenrah, I'm gonna need your help
你懂板上的文字，你送大家回去
This is your tablet. You know
the instructions. You get everyone back
有个人得看看这个
come on. There's somebody
who's gotta see this
他们每季付A-Rod这么多钱
what I'm saying is, for the type of money
that they pay A-Rod...
他每季都该打赢世界大赛
...he ought to be bringing home
a world Series trophy every season
你懂我的意思吧？
You know what I mean?
谁来帮它们清大便啊？
Now, who they gonna get
to clean up all that doo-doo?
-伊努特人
-在
-Inuit.
-Yeah
一个陶土士兵
one terracotta soldier
-维京海盗
-在
-vikings.
-Right
-羊鸵
-欢迎回来，女士们
-AIpaca.
-welcome back, ladies
-骆马
-嘿
-Llama.
-Hey
维京海盗
viking guys
你们在化石森林古迹
Do me a favor. Your fellows
made some funerAL pyre...
搞了个火葬之类的东西
去清干净
...in Petrified wood. Go clean that up
好吗？谢谢
okay? Thank you
他回来了
我来处理这烦人的家伙
-He's back.
-All right, I'll deAL with this joker
大麋鹿，你过不来的
Hey, hey, Moose.
It's not gonna happen, buddy. All right?
你头上的角会卡住
I told you, you can't come through
with those antlers
带着你的驯鹿朋友去上货区
So you and your caribou buddy
gotta go around to the loading dock
-劳伦斯
-泰迪
-Lawrence!
-Hey, Teddy
真高兴看到完整的你
Great to see you in one piece
莎卡佳哩弄点热腊就黏好了
Sakagawea, a little hot wax,
and I'm a new man
赖瑞？
Larry?
我说过我不是跟你开玩笑
I told you I wasn't making fun of you
-我知道
-泰迪？
-I know.
-Teddy?
老天
oh, my God
你想见见她吗？
wanna meet her?
-想
-好
-Yeah?
-Yeah
来吧
okay, come on
罗斯福总统，这是我朋友贝嘉
Excuse me. President Roosevelt,
this is my friend Rebecca
-幸会
-你好
-An honor.
-Hi
这位是莎卡佳歪
And this is Sakagawea
-哩
-wea.
-wea
wea
她有一些问题想问你
I think she has a few questions
she wants to ask you
你超赞的，我是你的超级粉丝
You rock. I am a big fan
你想知道什么？
what would you like to know?
我不知道该从何问起
well, I mean,
I don't know where to start, but...
-达摩祖师，合十答礼
-到
-one Buddha.
-check
两匹斑马
Two zebras
-好，到
-德克斯，欢迎回来
-Right. check.
-Dexter! welcome back
德克斯，我们和好吧？
Hey, Dex, so look.
No hard feelings, all right?
-劳伦斯
-你看到了
-Lawrence!
-You saw!
-你看到他打我了
-谁比较高等？
-You saw what he did just then!
-who's evolved?
-我
-谁比较高等？
-I am.
-who's evolved?
我！
I am!
很好
Good
全员到齐
well, they're all here
干得好
大家都回来了
well done. Everyone's in
是啊，不过K
Yeah, well...
没有全部
...not everyone
我们今晚失去了几个好小子
we lost a couple of good, little men
out there tonight
伟大的胜利总是会有些许牺牲
with great victory comes great sacrifice
是啊
Yeah
爸？你看
Dad, look
好耶！
Bully!
你没那么容易甩掉我们的
You ain't getting rid of us that easy
明晚见？劳伦斯
Until tomorrow evening, Lawrence?
我不知道，泰迪
Yeah. I don't know about that, Teddy
这次我可能搞不定了
It's gonna be tough
to tALk my way out of this one
若真是那样
well, if that's indeed the case...
那么就此道别了，朋友
...then it's farewell, my friend
尼克？
Nick?
你父亲是英雄
Your father's a great man
我知道
I know
我跟你说过了
Told you
晚安
All right. Good night
不，是早安
No, Lawrence. Good day
泰迪？
Hey, Teddy?
谢了
Thanks
这是纽约一台，新闻台
You're watching New YorK 1.
News all morning
今天地上铺了一层新雪
ThanKs for joining us.
There is a fresh blanKet of snow
不过纽约人谈论的可不是这个
But it's not the snow
that's got New YorKers talKing
他们谈的是雪上的东西
西81街上有恐龙脚印
It's what's in the snow. There are
dinosaur tracKs along West 81 st Street
那些脚印是暴龙脚印
Here's the remarKable video. These appear
to be Tyrannosaurus Rex tracKs...
足迹直接延伸至自然历史博物馆
...and they lead straight
to the Museum of Natural History
当局发现地铁里有史前洞穴划
Authorities have found what appear to be
cave drawings in the subway
尼安德塔人在博物馆屋顶
这是骗局还是公关活动？
Neanderthals atop the museum roof.
Elaborate hoax or publicity stunt?
（家庭影片
博物馆之迷）
由你来决定
但有件事很确定
You be the judge,
but one thing's for sure:
自然历史博物馆的人员
真是使出了浑身绝技
The folKs at the Natural History Museum
have really outdone them--
你有何解释？
Any explanation at all?
没，没有解释
No. Got nothing
好
Good
我要拿回你的钥匙和手电筒
I'll take your keys and your flashlight
大家，跟我来
Folks, this way
我叫尼克达理
我的职场父母要介绍的是我爸
My name is Nick Daley.
My career Day parent is my dad
他是自然历史博物馆的夜班警卫
He's the night watchman
at the Museum of NaturAL History
尼克说过了
Hey, how's it going? well, Nicky said it:
我是自然历史博物馆的夜班警卫
I'm the night watchman
at the Museum of NaturAL History
在那里，历史栩栩如生
Let me tell you something:
That's when history comes alive
你们有多少人到过那里？
How many of you guys
have been over to the museum?
得分！
GoAL!
嘿，时间晚了
你要回家了吗？
Hey, it's getting late.
Are you ready to go home?
还没
Nope
冲啊
Let's ride
赖瑞很好心没举发我们
不过这太扯了
It was nice of Larry not to rat us out,
but this is ridiculous
我们是夜班警卫，不是清洁工
we're night watchmen, not janitors!
你们好好干
Gentlemen, you're doing a terrific job
我去打个盹
I'll gonna catch a few Z's
你不能走
You ain't going nowhere
快给我拖地
Start mopping, hot dog
这边
over here